Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- VISUAL MATERIAL, 1927 (Photo file)
  - Includes portrait prints of Petr Struve and drawings of Petr Struve and Simon Frank, as well as prints of Russian Civil War in the Far East (Chita, Irkutsk and Vladivostok) (Envelope A)
- MEMORABILIA, undated (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Order of St. Savva (Serbia) belonging to Petr Struve
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1903-1968 (Boxes 51-58)
  - Correspondence, 1903-1968
    Arrangement Statement
    Arranged in two groups, then alphabetically thereunder by name of correspondent.
    - Struve, Petr, 1903-1943
      - General, 1919-1943
        - 1919 (Box-folder 51: 1-5)
        - 1925 (Box-folder 51: 6)
        - 1926 (Box-folder 51: 7)
        - 1927-1929 (Box-folder 51: 8)
        - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 51: 9)
        - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 51: 10)
      - Bakhmet'ev (Bakhmet'eff), Mary, 1903-1904 (Box-folder 51: 11)
      - Bazili, Nikolai Aleksandrovich, 1919 (Box-folder 51: 12)
      - Borman, A., 1919 (Box-folder 51: 13)
      - El'iashev, B., 1919 (Box-folder 51: 14)
      - Fedorov, Mikhail N., 1919 (Box-folder 51: 15)
      - Gessen, I. V., 1919 (Box-folder 51: 16)
      - Hoare, Sir Samuel, 1919 (Box-folder 51: 17)
      - Kartashev, Anton V., 1919 (Box-folder 51: 18)
      - Konchevskaia, N., 1919 (Box-folder 51: 19)
      - Ostroukhov, P. A., 1919-1929 (Box-folder 51: 20)
      - Rist, Charles, 1919 (Box-folder 51: 21)
      - Sukhotin, H., 1942 (Box-folder 51: 22)
      - Tyrkova-Williams, Ariadna, 1919 (Box-folder 51: 23)
      - Williams, Harold, 1919 (Box-folder 51: 24)
    - Struve family, 1914-1968
      - Struve, Aleksei, 1914-1968 (Box-folder 51: 25-30)
      - Struve, Arkadii, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 52: 1)
      - Struve, Gleb, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 52: 2)
      - Struve, Konstantin, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 52: 3-6)
      - Struve, Lev, 1923-1928 (Box-folder 52: 7-9)
      - Struve, Nina, 1920-1943
        - General, 1920-1943
          - 1920-1922 (Box-folder 52: 10)
          - 1923-1924 (Box-folder 52: 11)
          - 1925 (Box-folder 52: 12)
          - 1926 (Box-folder 52: 13-14)
          - 1927 (Box-folder 52: 15-16)
          - 1928-1929 (Box-folder 53: 1)
          - 1930-1932 (Box-folder 53: 2)
          - 1937-1941 (Box-folder 53: 3)
          - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 53: 4)
        - Struve, Aleksei, 1922-1942
          - Undated (Box-folder 53: 5-6)
          - 1922 (Box-folder 53: 7)
          - 1923 (Box-folder 53: 8-9)
          - 1924 (Box-folder 53: 10-12)
          - 1925 (Box-folder 53: 13-14)
          - 1926 (Box-folder 54: 1-3)
          - 1927 (Box-folder 54: 4-5)
          - 1928 (Box-folder 54: 6-7)
          - 1929 (Box-folder 54: 8-10)
          - 1930 (Box-folder 54: 11-12)
          - 1931 (Box-folder 55: 1)
          - 1932 (Box-folder 55: 2)
          - 1933 (Box-folder 55: 3-4)
          - 1934 (Box-folder 55: 5)
          - 1935 (Box-folder 55: 6)
          - 1936 (Box-folder 55: 7)
          - 1937 (Box-folder 55: 8)
          - 1938 (Box-folder 55: 9)
          - 1939 (Box-folder 55: 10)
          - 1940-1942 (Box-folder 55: 11)
        - Struve, Arkadii, 1925-1932
          - 1925-1926 (Box-folder 55: 12)
          - 1927 (Box-folder 55: 13)
          - 1932 (Box-folder 55: 14)
        - Struve, Iuliia, 1923-1932 (Box-folder 55: 15)
        - Struve, Konstantin, 1925-1927
          - 1925 (Box-folder 55: 16)
          - 1926 (Box-folder 55: 17)
          - 1927 (Box-folder 55: 18)
        - Struve, Lev, 1925-1928
          - 1925-1926 (Box-folder 55: 19)
          - 1927 (Box-folder 56: 1-2)
          - 1928 (Box-folder 56: 3-5)
        - Struve, Petr, 1925 (Box-folder 56: 6)
  - Career file, 1918-1933
    Includes records, correspondence, newsletters, and other material relating to Petr Struve's career as a Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Russian Provisional Government.
    - Ministry dossiers of special files compiled for Petr Struve, 1918-1920
      Include political reports and analyses, correspondence, and notes, organized by general topic as originally received.
      - Estonia, 1919 (Box-folder 56: 7)
      - Finland, 1919 (Box-folder 56: 8)
      - Krym, 1919 (Box-folder 56: 9)
      - Russia, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 56: 10-11)
      - Siberia, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 56: 12)
      - Turkey, 1919 (Box-folder 56: 13)
      - Ukraine, 1919 (Box-folder 57: 1-2)
      - Zakavkaz'e, 1919 (Box-folder 57: 3)
    - Speeches and writings, 1919, 1933
      - General, 1933, undated (Box-folder 57: 4-6)
        Includes typed draft of article, manuscript notes, and draft notes for untitled speeches on Russian histrory.
      - "The Bolshevik Terror; Russian Professor's Escape," Petr Struve interview to Reuters, London, 1919 (Box-folder 57: 7)
    - Reports, newsletters, and clippings, 1919
      - "Izvestiia 'Osvaga,' materialy dlia informirovaniia pechati," No. 107, 1919 (Box-folder 57: 8)
      - "Politicheskaia Svodka, Otdel Propagandy Osobogo Soveshchaniia pri Glavnokomanduuishchem Vooruzhennymi Silami Iuga Rossii," Nos. 12-148, Ekaterinodar, 1919
        - Nos. 12, 14, 18, 20-24, 26 (Box-folder 57: 9)
        - Nos. 30-32, 34-35, 45, 65 (Box-folder 57: 10)
        - Nos. 72-73, 100-101, 113-117 (Box-folder 57: 11)
        - Nos. 118-125 (Box-folder 57: 12)
        - Nos. 127, 132-136 (Box-folder 57: 13)
        - Nos. 137-140, 144, 146, 148 (Box-folder 57: 14)
      - Russia's foreign trade reports, Stockholm, 1919
        The files are in their original order using original folder headings.
        - List of enclosures (Box-folder 57: 15)
        - "Russian Iron Industry and Its Possibilities" (Box-folder 57: 16)
        - "Construction of Agricultural Machinery in Russia and Import from Abroad" (Box-folder 57: 17)
        - "Memorandum on the Locomotive Building Industry in Russia" (Box-folder 58: 1)
        - "Memorandum on Russia's Hallway Reconstruction by A. P. Mestechersky" (Box-folder 58: 2)
        - "Russia's Position on the International Grain Market" (Box-folder 58: 3)
        - "The Russian Oil Industry and the Export from Russia of Naphtha Products" (Box-folder 58: 4)
        - "Russia's Butter Exports" (Box-folder 58: 5)
        - "Export of Sugar from Russia Abroad" (Box-folder 58: 6)
        - "Export of Spirits of Wine from Russia Abroad" (Box-folder 58: 7)
        - "Russia's Foreign Trade in Wool" (Box-folder 58: 8)
        - "Export of Russian Furs" (Box-folder 58: 9)
        - "Export of Wines Abroad" (Box-folder 58: 10)
        - "Russia's Foreign Trade in Timber" (Box-folder 58: 11)
        - "Export of Tobacco and Its Products from Russia" (Box-folder 58: 12)
        - "Russia's Foreign Trade in Flax" (Box-folder 58: 13)
        - "Export of Horses' Manes and Tails from Russia Abroad" (Box-folder 58: 14)
        - "Table of Russian Imports" (Box-folder 58: 15)
        - "Table of Exports from Russia" (Box-folder 58: 16)
        - "Russian Joint Stock Banks in 1914-1917 (General Statistics)" (Box-folder 58: 17)
        - "Examination of the Principal Branches of Industry in Siberia" (Box-folder 58: 18)
      - Svobodnaia Rech, 1919 (Box-folder 58: 19)
        Contains clippings on Russia, agriculture, and politics.
      - "Telegrafnyi Biulleten' (Voennaia srochnaia)," Nos. 88, 89, 91, 99, 100, 1919 (Box-folder 58: 20)
      - "Za granitsei," No. 295, 1919 (Box-folder 58: 21)